## **ANASTASIA STOWERS**

(210) 723-9168 ♦ anastasia.k.stowers@gmail.com ♦ San Antonio, TX ♦ http://anastasia.stowers.info ♦ github.com/anastasiastowers

#### **OBJECTIVE**

Ruby on Rails developer with over 3 years technical experience. Specializes in back end development with a strong front end foundation. Seeking employment as a Ruby developer in a position that entails the continual acquisition of new skills on an engaged team.

## **TECHNICAL SKILLS**

## </>> languages

HTML - ERB - HAML CSS - SASS - BEM JS - jQuery - AJAX Ruby PHP

#### >\_ development tools

Git - Github Bash - Zsh - Fish NPM - Bower - Yarn

# **frameworks**

Ruby on Rails Sinatra React Jekyll Ionic

## data storage

Redis SQL

ElasticSearch

## automated testing

Rspec + Factory Girl Capybara Selenium

## CMSs

Wordpress Pimcore Contentful Shopify

## RESTful APIs

## design

Sketch - Wireframes Responsive Design X-browser support UCD - UDD

#### \* CSS frameworks

Foundation Bootstrap Skeleton Bourbon

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

#### **Chargify - Developer II**

Sep 2018 - Present

- Worked on the Analytics and Rapid Response development teams for an enterprise Elastic Billing company building a monolithic Ruby on Rails application with over 20 developers across the US, Canada, and Poland.
- Alternated first responder duties and rapidly responded to incoming Github issues elevated from Tier 2 Support for our merchants' complex B2B SaaS Billing scenarios, incorporating a TDD workflow.
- Built advanced finance-focused Analytics features involving mass, high-speed data collection from ElasticSearch.
- Additional responsibilities included stringent code review, defining concrete tasks for abstract product feature requests, and improving Help and API documentation for end users.
- Introduced processes to identify and resolve unreliable tests streamlining our CI/CD pipeline.
- Tutored junior-level developers on React, Rails, and best development practices.

## **Elevate Systems - Contract Web Developer**

Aug 2017 - Sep 2018

- Built Sinatra applications to process and deliver dynamic, arrangeable content using the Contentful Content Delivery API to an elegant website.
- Prepared custom Contentful content models to meet client's needs for content types, highly customizable content hierarchies, and environment-restricted content.
- Built Ruby on Rails application for e-commerce business with product referral bonus system.
- Implemented caching strategies with Redis to improve load times and reduce dependency on external services.
- Deployed Ruby application on Ubuntu with Nginx managing the reverse proxy to point to a Standalone Passenger.

#### **Lightning Jar - Contract Front-end Developer**

May 2016 - July 2017

- Collaborated full-time (40+ hours/week) with a diverse, multilevel team across the country to create quality apps for numerous small to medium-large businesses (including BlueLine Rental, Beam Suntory, and Tremor Video).
- Used a combination of modern CMSs (Pimcore), bug-tracking applications (Asana & Wrike), and communication tools (Slack) paired with Agile methodologies.
- Consistently contributed to and built custom back-end PHP features.

#### **Element Thirty - Contract Front-end Developer**

Apr - July 2016

- · Subcontracted to complete various Wordpress-based websites, including for their clients Foster CM Group and QSI.
- Developed all designs into pixel-perfect, responsive solutions.

#### **RELEVANT PROJECTS**

## **Automated Wedding Invitations**

- Built a RoR application utilizing the Twilio API in order to send invitations to wedding invitees, receive RSVP data, and categorize, adjust, and record invitee needs.
- Set up dashboard to concisely view key data.
- · Built full test suite using TDD with Rspec + FactoryGirl

### Missionspree

- Constructed a CSS framework using Bourbon SASS for a small experimental social ecommerce Ruby on Rails application while upholding modern standards for design and development.
- · Led a user-centered design process using Sketch.

#### **EDUCATION**

Austin College '15, GPA: 3.6, Environmental Studies & German Majors, Japanese Minor, Study Abroad BCA Marburg '14